## Nicholas G. McMullen

Certified Total Rewards & People Analytics Professional Greater Phoenix Area, Arizona, USA e: nicholasgmcmullen@gmail.com w: nickmcmullen.github.io s: linkedin.com/in/nicholas-mcmullen

# Summary

Analytically-inclined, people-oriented HR practitioner with experience supporting executives and front-line teams as a strategic partner. Skilled in analyzing people programs and making sense out of data, rewards design and management, human resources operations, and onboarding. Experienced at implementing, integrating, and managing a variety of HR technology solutions, managing rewards programs, and leading people-people teams.

# **Employment**

### **Compensation and People Analytics Lead**

January 2022 - Present

RStudio PBC Remote. USA

- Establish dedicated compensation consultation function
- Conduct job analysis, evaluation, and benchmarking for all current and new company jobs
- Implement Radford salary survey and benchmarking tool
- Architect suite of automated dashboards using an R-powered shiny app to provide key stakeholders with a high-level overview of employee lifecycle metrics
- Act as lead People Ops stakeholder for building automated data exchange between ATS and HRIS
- Lead automated data exchange setup between HRIS and employee engagement/listening platform
- Build and automated employee lifecycle surveys including a 90-day new hire survey and annual employee engagement survey

#### **People Operations Partner**

January 2021 - January 2022

RStudio PBC Remote, USA

- Established company wide job code architecture
- Assisted with talent management initiatives and employee relations matters
- Architected career frameworks for technical staff
- Created and led "manager meetup" development calls
- Conducted 90-day check ins with all new employees
- managed job analysis, evaluation, and benchmarking process

#### **Senior Specialist Total Rewards Content**

September 2020 - January 2021

WorldatWork Remote, USA

- Authored a complete practice strategy with market research for executive leadership,
- Wrote data taxonomy for Salesforce CRM environment and defined new key workflows
- Advised leadership on marketplace education and certification trends in total rewards

#### **Manager People Systems and Analytics**

January 2020 - September 2020

Alliance Residential Company

Phoenix, AZ, USA

- Oversaw operation and management of all people-related systems, including HRIS, ATS, compensation, and corporate social responsibility.
- Implemented and integrated new CSR platform with HRIS.
- Managed the calculation and processing of quarterly bonuses for 2500+ site and regional operations employees.
- Acted as HR liaison to the company compensation committee.
- Assisted with M&A activities related to HR data during Greystar/Alliance merger.

#### **Manager Talent Analytics and Operations**

May 2018 - January 2020

Alliance Residential Company

Phoenix, AZ, USA

- Led configuration and ongoing optimization efforts of iCIMS ATS.
- Built and automated suite of Tableau dashboards for talent acquisition executive team for monthly reporting requirements.
- Automated monthly recruiting fee bill-back process, increasing accuracy of processing to 99% and saving 25 monthly hours of manual reporting and auditing.
- Implemented Salary.com CompAnalyst and conducted market benchmarking for all company jobs.
- Managed centralized recruiting coordinator team of two responsible for administrative and compliance-related onboarding tasks that successfully onboarded 2000+ employees over 20 months across 25 US states.

#### **Learning and Development Intern**

June 2017 - August 2017

Alliance Residential Company Phoenix, AZ, USA

- Analyzed a pilot sales training program for impact on closing leases, resulting in full adoption of the program organization-wide.
- Restructured company knowledge bank in Cornerstone OnDemand LMS.
- Converted, redesigned, and published online company training courses from Adobe Captivate format to Articulate Rise 360 in Cornerstone OnDemand LMS.
- Managed pool and HVAC maintenance certification program, including tracking in Cornerstone OnDemand LMS and conducting ongoing compliance reporting.

## Education

B.A. magna cum laude, Applied Mathematics and Statistics

August 2014 - May 2018

Macalester College St. Paul, MN, USA

Certifications

**Certified Compensation Professional (CCP)** 

WorldatWork

Expires November 2023

**Global Remuneration Professional (GRP)** 

WorldatWork

Expires November 2023

Professional in Human Resources (PHR)

Human Resources Certification Institute (HRCI)

Expires February 2024

**Tableau Desktop 2019 Certified Associate (expired)** 

Tableau Software

Expired October 2021

#### Skills

- Base pay design and administration
- Job analysis, documentation, and evaluation
- Incentive compensation program management
- HRIS integration and administration
- ATS implementation, administration
- LMS implementation, administration
- Talent onboarding process development and management
- People program analysis and evaluation
- Data cleaning and manipulation
- Process improvement, design, and automation
- People team management

# Software Experience

- R programming
- Shiny app development
- RStudio IDE
- Radford Benchmarking
- BambooHR HRIS
- Greenhouse.io ATS
- Culture Amp
- Salary.com CompAnalyst

- UltiPro HRIS (UKG)
- iCIMS ATS
- Fuse LXP
- Cornerstone OnDemand LMS
- Qualtrics